tactilecrm.com 2018-06-27

# Our Privacy Policy

We take your privacy and the protection of your personal data seriously. We will only store, process and disclose your personal data in accordance with the law. We have a Data Protection Officer (DPO) and they may be contacted via matters of data and/or privacy at the following email address: support@tactilecrm.com. 

**What kinds of personal information about you do we process?**

  * Personal contact details, such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address.
  * Your date of birth, nationality, and gender.
  * Records of contact you have with us, such as phone numbers and email addresses that you may contact us from.
  * Details of products and services you hold with us.
  * The usage of those products and services, including time spent and features accessed.
  * Information about your User Agent and IP address used to access our services.
  * Information about your employment, such as job title and employer details.

**What is the source of your personal information?**

We will collect personal data from you directly, or from third parties using our software to store your personal information for their business needs.

When you access this Web site, some information such as the site that referred you to the Tactile CRM Web site, your IP address, and your email address may be automatically collected as part of the operation of this Web site. We may use this information to generate user profiles and to personalise our Web site to your particular interests. 

**What do we use your personal data for?**

  * Assessing our products and services, to allow us to continue their development and tailor your experiences with them.
  * Managing the product or service you have with us.
  * To perform and/or test the performance of, our products, services and internal processes.
  * To improve the operation of our business.
  * To follow guidance and best practice under the change to rules of governmental and regulatory bodies.
  * To comply with legal and regulatory obligations, requirements and guidance.

omelett.es ltd does not share information with other companies other than its own associates, and does not sell its user information. Any personal information we collect may be used for such purposes as processing transactions, customer service, marketing, product and service development, recruiting and facilitating subsequent use of this Web site. We explicitly reserve the right to disclose any such personal information if required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, respond to claims, or protect the rights, property or safety of our company, employees, customers, or the public. 

We cannot be responsible for the content or privacy policy on sites run by others, including those to whom we have linked, and you should satisfy yourself of those sites' privacy policy prior to revealing any personal information. You should also note that jurisdictions outside the European Union (including the United States) may not have data protection laws which are regarded as adequate by the European Commission. 

**What are the legal grounds for our processing of your personal information?**

Where we require your data to provide you with our products or services, manage your accounts, or update your existing records.

Where it is in our legitimate interests to use your data, such as the management of your subscribed products and services, the keeping of our accounts, the testing of our services and products, or to follow guidance and recommended best practice of government and regulatory bodies. 

To comply with our legal obligations, such as to send you communications where you have consented to being contacted.

**Where is my data kept?**

Tactile CRM is operated by Omelett.es Ltd, a UK-based company. However, we may require the use of data storage facilities (e.g. databases) located in other countries, in order to maintain availability of our products and services. When this is done, we'll make sure safeguards are in place to protect your data.

**What are your rights?**

  * The right to be informed about the processing of your personal information
  * The right to have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate and to have incomplete personal information completed
  * The right to object to processing of your personal information
  * The right to restrict processing of your personal information
  * The right to have your personal information erased (the “right to be forgotten”)
  * The right to request access to your personal information and to obtain information about how we process it
  * The right to move, copy or transfer your personal information (“data portability”)
  * Rights in relation to automated decision making which has a legal effect or otherwise significantly affects you

We cannot provide you with products or services without certain information. Where this is optional, we'll make it clear.

If your details change, or if you wish to communicate with us regarding any other data-related matter, please contact us using the details at the top of this page.

We will keep your data for as long as we have reasonable business needs, such as managing your accounts with us. Where required by law, we may keep data for a retention period in line with legal and regulatory requirements.
